<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Paul's blog</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Paul's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:59:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Space filling curves and CNN</title><link>/post/space-filling-curves-and-transformer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:59:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/space-filling-curves-and-transformer/</guid><description>👷🏻 this is a work in progress 🔧
Sometimes by exploring incongruous ideas, one can make interesting discoveries. This is know as serendipity in science, with penicillin being a famous example of an unplanned discovery.
What I experimented with this week-end… is no such case. 😅
In the spirit of not holding back negative results though, and for the unlikely possibility that it turns out helpful for someone, I&amp;rsquo;ll share it regardless!</description></item><item><title>Creating a static blog, the convoluted way</title><link>/post/creating-a-static-blog-the-convoluted-way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:16:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/creating-a-static-blog-the-convoluted-way/</guid><description>TLDR: I wanted to create a static blog while being able to type articles from a nice UI, from anywhere. It is quite straightforward with forestry + hugo + github pages. Jump to the solution.
Motivation If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to create a blog, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck! There are countless tools to help you get up and running in a few minutes. For example Hugo will generate a static site from a few markdown files, and pushing it to github in a repository named YOUR_USERNAME.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>About me Hi there, I&amp;rsquo;m Paul Willot. I grew up in France and moved to Japan for my first job. I started as a programmer, mainly for tasks centered on machine learning, and recently moved into project and team leadership.
I enjoy talking about machine learning, programming, sysadmin and life in Japan.
Though I can&amp;rsquo;t promise an immediate reply, feel free to email me. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to talk to you!</description></item></channel></rss>