<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Paul's blog</title><link>/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Paul's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 14:05:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Placeholder</title><link>/post/placeholder/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 14:05:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/placeholder/</guid><description>Placeholder</description></item><item><title>Basic watermark removal in videos</title><link>/post/basic-watermark-removal-in-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 06:30:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/basic-watermark-removal-in-videos/</guid><description>The general problem of completing images and videos depending on a mask is called inpainting, and numerous methods exists to tackle this problem in ingenuous ways.
However most approaches are relatively costly to run, especially without a graphic card, so I wanted to see what result we could get with simple and fast methods.
You can find the code for the steps below in this repository.
To start, we need to find the mask, which correspond to the location of pixels to remove.</description></item><item><title>Space filling curves and CNN</title><link>/post/space-filling-curves-and-transformer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 11:59:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/space-filling-curves-and-transformer/</guid><description>👷🏻 this is a work in progress 🔧
Sometimes by exploring incongruous ideas, one can make interesting discoveries. This is know as serendipity in science, with penicillin being a famous example of an unplanned discovery.
What I experimented with this week-end… is no such case. 😅
In the spirit of not holding back negative results though, and for the unlikely possibility that it turns out helpful for someone, I&amp;rsquo;ll share it regardless!</description></item><item><title>Creating a static blog, the convoluted way</title><link>/post/creating-a-static-blog-the-convoluted-way/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 06:16:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/creating-a-static-blog-the-convoluted-way/</guid><description>TLDR: I wanted to create a static blog while being able to type articles from a nice UI, from anywhere. It is quite straightforward with forestry + hugo + github pages. Jump to the solution.
Motivation If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to create a blog, you&amp;rsquo;re in luck! There are countless tools to help you get up and running in a few minutes. For example Hugo will generate a static site from a few markdown files, and pushing it to github in a repository named YOUR_USERNAME.</description></item></channel></rss>